# JOHN WOFFINDIN

j.woffindin@gmail.com

+64 (0)21 558671

#### SENIOR DEVELOPER, SYSTEMS INTEGRATOR, DEVOPS

#### **Profile**

Software Engineer with solid Development, Systems Integration and Architecture experience. Throughout my career I have shown myself to be a self-motivated, reliable and adaptable team player. I am a successful problem solver and see projects through to completion.

Skills

Systems Integrator Developer Systems Architect

Infrastructure, application build and deployment automation, operations support. Multi-lingual OO developer, TDD/BDD, API Design, Billing Systems, Mobile Web, Performance Optimisation. Proven record in end-toend delivery of complex, high-availability, systems.

**Technical** 

I only list skills used in the last 2 years.

Unix, Linux, OS/X	Ruby, Perl, Shell	Rails, Sinatra, Rack
Rspec, Cucumber, TDD	Chef, Capistrano	SQL, Postgres, Oracle
HTML, HAML, CSS, LESS, SCSS	Javascript, jQuery, jQuery Mobile	XML, XSL, XSLT, WADL
Java, JVM Tuning	Git, Github	Apache

# Experience

#### SLA Mobile Ltd

Vodafone: Deployment Automation Consulting - London, UK

Jul 2013-current

<u>Vodafone Group</u> (VFG) are in the initial stages of a 10-year project to completely upgrade and centralize <u>BSS</u> infrastructure for 14 EMEA carriers.

I was engaged to build a proof-of-concept multi-domain/multi-carrier Continuous Delivery pipeline using a mixture of pre-selected vendor and OSS tools. The objective of this project is to validate technical feasibility and document risks in scaling CI/CD to the planned 190+production environments.

Automation, Chef, Jenkins, Vagrant, Maven, Artifactory, AWS EC2, HP Quality Centre, IBM Rational Team Concert, MCollective, Ruby, BMC BladeLogic

# Alacrity: Lead Engineer - NZ

Dec 2010-current

Vodafone Ireland wanted to leverage the Group <u>Click-to-Bill</u> service for national merchants and aggregators. This is not practical for a number of reasons including prohibitive internal on-boarding costs and a merchant engagement and support processes geared towards large global entities, such as Google, RIM and Microsoft.

SLA Mobile was engaged by Vodafone Ireland to provide a solution catering these local merchants and developers. Based on the customers initial requirements, I developed and delivered a self-service developer portal and a set of billing and customer-care APIs. It took 4 months from initial customer engagement until the first production release.

The initial product has grown to become <u>Alacrity</u>, SLA Mobile's <u>Direct Carrier Billing</u> SaaS solution marketed to carriers world wide. Alacrity now supports a range of customer and merchant channels including the RESTAPIs, desktop and mobile browser, and an in-app purchase support.

Until late 2012 myself and a KL-based SI were the sole technical resources working on Alacrity. My responsibilities also covered production support, product management, presales support, and delivery of technical and non-technical documentation.

Alacrity is now maintained by a small DevOps team of 5, including myself. We use CI/TDD, RSpec for unit, functional and integration tests; Cucumber, Selenium and Vagrant for automated acceptance tests. We use campfire for team communication. <a href="https://hubot.nubmates.nubmates.nubmates">hubot</a> automates many tasks including application deployments.

Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, RSpec, Cucumber, Chef, Vagrant, Capistrano, Apache, nginx, Postgres, Mongodb, Memcache, AWS EC2, Ubuntu, Jenkins, Github, Gitlab, Campfire, Hubot, Trello, Code Climate, REST XML/JSON, New Relic, HTML, CSS2, LESS, Bootstrap

Vodafone Hutchison Australia required new billing adapters for their ER platform in order to support several Vodafone Group <a href="CTB">CTB</a> propositions, including integration with <a href="Google">Google</a>, Microsoft.

In addition to the technical requirements and design documentation, I implemented the Java-based payment adapters, supported UAT, and provided go-live and post-launch support together with the project SI and another Senior developer.

TDD practices were followed for the Java development, with majority tests written using Rspec under JRuby. Final delivery consisted of about 1,100 tests for around 16k lines of Java adapter code.

Java, Spring, Hibernate, JPA, Oracle DB, JBoss, Solaris, JRuby, RSpec, RR, SOAP/REST, Eclipse, GIT.

#### Mondrian API: Architect / Developer - NZ/UK

Mar 2010-Aug 2011

Mondrian is a set of Vodafone specific Web Services derived from Parlay-X whereby individual carriers can expose a consistent set of capabilities to the Vodafone Group Global Integration Gateway (GIG). By 2010 the Mondrian V1 solutions implemented by many EMEA carriers were bespoke solutions offered by large vendors and subject to lock-in through the use of proprietary technologies and closed black-box solutions.

While working with the GIG development team in London I identified a commercial opportunity for SLA Mobile to to enter the Mondrian market with a product based primarily on OSS components and to use an OSS-style approach to product development between carriers.

I wrote and presented the original business case, and addition to managing a small DevOps team, looked after ESB configuration and customization (mostly lots of XSLT transformations), automated infrastructure and application build/deployments, and implementing several of the Perl-based reference services.

This project delivered a full "reference" implementation of the first generation Mondrian APIs based on OSS components.

WSO2 ESB, Java, Spring, JBoss, Axis2, Perl, XSLT, SOAP, Maven, GIT, M4, Ruby

#### Vodafone: Business Process Analyst - London/Düsseldorf

2009

Consultant to Vodafone Group alongside the GIG development, QA and production teams based in Düsseldorf and London. I evaluated their development, release and support processes and wrote a detailed report highlighting inefficiencies in their current processes and provided specific recommendations that leading to improved product quality and reduced delivery times.

#### Vodafone: Presales Engineer - London UK

2009

Technical pre-sales support for the UK sales team covering various EMEA-based projects. I was directly responsible for supporting the sales team, assisting on RFP responses, preparing technical prototypes and detailed design documentation as required.

### Fox Media: Mobile Portal Developer - NZ

2008

International mobile content retailer <u>Jamba!</u> required a site to support their launch into the Asian markets (Indonesia primarily). Jamba's internal development team was not able to deliver within the time-lines required by the business, so SLA Mobile was engaged to deliver mobile and web portals selling ringtones, wallpapers and related mobile content within 6 weeks.

I delivered the content management and mobile portal under the 6 weeks, and the KL team delivered a Java-based desktop web solution.

The platform consisted of a rails based content management ingestion platform, and consumer facing portal for content discovery and purchase. The solution consisted of the portal itself rendering device agnostic semantic markup, and a transformation proxy responsible for device-specific content rendering.

Challenges in this project mostly stemmed from the diverse population of devices with simple, often buggy, browsers and limited media support. A lot of effort went into content and delivery optimization while ensuring compatibility with a wide range of devices. It was successful enough that we later rebranded for Jamba to support Vodafone Qatar.

Ruby, Rails 2, Phusion Passenger, Postgres, XSLT, XML, WML 1/2, ImageMagick, WURFL, XHTML MP, HTML, CSS, CentOS, Capistrano.

# Vodafone Live!: Architect / Systems Integrator - NZ

2008

Architect and Lead Integrator for Vodafone Live! New Zealand and Australia. Responsibilities included design and documentation - gap analysis, architecture design, publishing and maintaining high level designs, server build specifications, network/communication specifications, software build, configuration, deployment,

integration, UAT and post-launch support and monitoring.

These releases have telco "HA" requirements, and the production environment alone included 22 separate customised software components deployed across 72 virtual and physical servers.

Built an multi-environment configuration and application deployment solution based on Capistrano replacing the manual approach taken by most other Vodafone carriers.

Responsible for supervision and coordination of a small team of integrators working on the project. On completion of this project I assumed the "Mobile Internet Architect" within Vodafone NZ for a period of several months until the role could be filled internally.

Vodafone SP 9.6 Corestack/ER, Apache, Java, Jboss, Solaris 10, Ruby, Oracle Database, Squid, Perl, RRD, Capistrano.

# Vodafone Live!: Migration Specialist - Europe / APAC

2004-2006

Responsibilities included working with the carriers on-site for preparation of initial Gap Analysis and High Level Designs. Coordination of development and deployment, product trouble-shooting and diagnosis, performance analysis, product knowledge transfer to the operator, technical documentation preparation, go-live and production support.

I was the primary product support consultant for Vodafone Portugal (2006), Greece (2005), and Croatia (2005). Secondary support for projects in Vodafone France, UK, Egypt, Spain and Italy.

Vodafone SP R5 & R7 Corestack/ER, Apache, Java, Jboss, WebLogic, Solaris 9/10, Oracle Database, Perl.

# Xoren Internet Solutions Group Ltd - Hamilton, NZ

# **Director and Senior Developer**

2000-2004

Co-founded a small web-development consulting firm with another developer and 2 graphic designers. Actively involved in all aspects of the project life cycle, from bidding and quoting on jobs, developing proposals, client communication, identifying and documenting requirements, software development, testing, project management, documentation, training and on-going support. Systems administrator for the website hosting service side of our business.

Perl, HTML, CSS, Postgres, Javascript, Apache, sendmail, Linux (Redhat and Debian).

# Contract Software Developer

### Mindz-i Group - Hamilton NZ

Feb 2000 - Jun 2004

Mindz-i was a small Software Solutions Company specialising in Digital Print and Prepress Markets. My role was design and Implementation of print procurement and digital asset management systems - primarily as a software architect and programmer, but also involved management and support of a small team of developers, and pre/post-sales support.

Perl, Python, HTML, CSS, XML, XSLT, Postgres, Javascript, SOAP, PDF, Apache,

## Contract Developer/Project Manager

# <u>InFront Ltd - UK</u> Mar 1999 - Dec 1999

Specification and development of Internet applications for a (then) leading UK e-commerce site. Responsible for a small team of developers working on back-end billing and dispatch systems. Software design and development, assigning and coordinating projects, tracking and reporting progress, supporting team members as required. Liaising with internal users of system to identify shortcomings of the system and identify potential efficiency improvements within the business.

Perl, Oracle DB, HTML, CSS, Linux, Solaris, Sybase SQL.

# Senior Developer and Systems Administrator

# WebMasters Ltd - NZ

Nov 1996 - Dec 1998

Internet software developer, network and Unix systems administration. Managed Unix Internet servers hosting hundreds of client sites. Primary contact for client technical queries. Built IP based radio network including routing and firewalls. Built and managed company intranet. Developed dynamic web sites using Perl CGI and database backends.

Linux, Apache, Perl, mSQL, MySQL, IP Networks.

# Contract Programmer Embedded Systems

Mirinz Dec 1995 - Oct 1996

Software development for the Electrical Engineering Group. Production of hardware specifications, development of DOS device drivers, production of embedded and PC-based applications systems meeting requirements identified by project scientists.

C++, C, Modula-2, Unix, DOS, Windows, Embedded Systemw

### Programmer-Analyst

# Physics Department, University of Waikato - Hamilton NZ

Mar 1994 - Dec 1995

Programming, network, and Unix administration, PC technical support. Design and build embedded control systems. Network administrator responsible for maintaining the departments OSF/1 server, general workstation and PC support within the department for staff and graduate students.

C, Pascal, Windows, OSF/1, AIX, AUX, Fortran, Embedded real-time control systems

# Personal Projects

# www.sharethemoment.me

#### Personal Website

A personal project, <u>www.sharethemoment.me</u> was written in my spare time for my brother as a way of validating a business idea he wanted to pursue.

Rails 3.2, Twitter bootstrap, Image Magick, RSpec, Heroku, Github, Postgres, Devise, OAuth

# Startup Weekend 2012

#### Category Winner

I took part in the Auckland Startup Weekend in 2012. The 3-person team I was in <a href="https://example.com/herepin">herepin</a> won the <a href="https://example.com/herepin">Catapult Prize</a> which included use of <a href="https://ecenter.com/herepin">ecenter</a> resources and a flight to San Francisco with a month at <a href="https://example.com/kiwi\_Landing\_Pad">Kiwi\_Landing\_Pad</a>. I resigned from the team a couple of months after the Startup Weekend because I was unable to devote the time the project deserved.

Rails, HTML5, Responsive Design, jQuery, jQuery Mobile, Geolocation, Devise, OAuth, Postgres

#### Education

# **Advanced Computer Communications**

Graduate level paper, University of Waikato - NZ

1995

Completed a post-graduate paper dealing with design and implementation of network protocols focusing on TCP/IP based protocols and firewall technology.

# BCMS (Bachelor of Computing and Mathematical Sciences)

University of Waikato - Hamilton NZ

1990 - 1993

Completed 7 Math, 14 Computer, and 6 Physics papers with 18 "A" and 8 "B" grades.

# Interests

I am a proud father of two. I love spending time with my children, biking, weight lifting, music, travel, photography, and good (Vegetarian) food. I am an avid reader of SciFi, and try to listen as many science and technical podcasts as time allows.

# References

References are available on request.